Guide to the Stanford University, Department of Economics, Records
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, Department of Economics, records
1941-1962
SC0072
Stanford University. Department of Economics.
1 Linear feet
Collection includes correspondence between the head of the department and the dean's office pertaining to curriculum, staffing, enrollments, budgets, and other administrative matters, 1945-55. Correspondents include Merrill K. Bennett, Bernard F. Haley, Clarence H. Faust, Edward S. Shaw, Ray Faulkner, and Kenneth J. Arrow. Of note in these files are correspondence and forms from the ASSU on a proposed faculty rating system, 1950, and a report on grade distributions in lower level courses in all schools for the 1948/49 year (both in box 1, folder 3). Other records include correspondence, minutes, reports, proposals and syllabi pertaining to national emergency courses, 1941-43; the Ford Foundation grant for research in economics, 1950-62; the proposed program in American studies, 1953; and the Committee on International Studies, 1947-48. The collection also includes annual reports from the department to the President, 1951-61.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Administrative transfer, 1970.
Information about Access
Access: partially restricted; consult the University Archivist for assistance.
Description of the Collection
Collection includes correspondence between the head of the department and the dean's office pertaining to curriculum, staffing, enrollments, budgets, and other administrative matters, 1945-55. Correspondents include Merrill K. Bennett, Bernard F. Haley, Clarence H. Faust, Edward S. Shaw, Ray Faulkner, and Kenneth J. Arrow. Of note in these files are correspondence and forms from the ASSU on a proposed faculty rating system, 1950, and a report on grade distributions in lower level courses in all schools for the 1948/49 year (both in box 1, folder 3). Other records include correspondence, minutes, reports, proposals and syllabi pertaining to national emergency courses, 1941-43; the Ford Foundation grant for research in economics, 1950-62; the proposed program in American studies, 1953; and the Committee on International Studies, 1947-48. The collection also includes annual reports from the department to the President, 1951-61.
Access Terms
Arrow, Kenneth Joseph, 1921-; Associated Students of Stanford University.; Bennett, Merrill K., 1898-1969.; Faulkner, Ray Nelson, 1906-1975.; Faust, Clarence H., (Clarence Henry), 1901-; Ford Foundation; Haley, Bernard Francis.; Shaw, Edward S. (Edward Stone).; Stanford University. Department of Economics.; Economics--Research.; Economics--Study and teaching (Higher).
Collection Contents
- Papers
  - Correspondence between Dean's Office-School of Social Sciences and Exec. Head of Dept. 1945-48 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence between Dean's Office-School of Humanities and Sciences and Exec. Head of Dept. 1948-49 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence between Dean's Office-School of Humanities and Sciences and Exec. Head of Dept. 1950 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence between Dean's Office-School ofHumanities and Sciences and Exec. Head of Dept. 1951-55 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - National Emergency Courses 1941-43 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Ford Grant for Research in Economics 1950-62 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence between President's Office and Exec. Head of Dept. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Program in American Studies 1953 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Committee on Lower Division 1950-52 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - University Committee on Intemational Studies 1947-48 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Annual Reports of Economics Dept. to President 1951-56 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Annual Reports of Economics Dept. to President 1957-61 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Requirements for Junior College Teaching Credential 1947-50 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Restricted Files
    The materials are restricted.
    - Scholarship Committee 1950-57 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Theodore H. Boggs (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Albert H. Bowker (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - J. B. Canning (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Leonard A. Doyle (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Herbert Goldhammer (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - W. S. Hopkins (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Roy J as tram (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Eliot Jones (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - W. O. Jones (Box 3, Folder 10)